let QUIZ = [
    {
        question_text: "Kittens are unable to retract their claws until they are ____ weeks of age.",
        answers: [
            "6 weeks",
            "1 week",
            "4 weeks",
            "8 weeks"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "4 weeks",
        image: "https://www.google.com/url?sa=i&source=images&cd=&ved=2ahUKEwjj8_LSsZ7jAhVECc0KHZKiBN8QjRx6BAgBEAU&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.thehappycatsite.com%2Fwhen-do-cats-stop-growing%2F&psig=AOvVaw3JMXMjc4OC3fc3YA0b6Hmx&ust=1562437027702191",
        alt: "kitten mewing"
    },
    {
        question_text: "All kittens are born with ___ color eyes.",
        answers: [
            "Blue",
            "Green",
            "Brown",
            "Purple"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Blue",
        image: "https://www.google.com/url?sa=i&source=images&cd=&ved=2ahUKEwjj8_LSsZ7jAhVECc0KHZKiBN8QjRx6BAgBEAU&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.thehappycatsite.com%2Fwhen-do-cats-stop-growing%2F&psig=AOvVaw3JMXMjc4OC3fc3YA0b6Hmx&ust=1562437027702191",
        alt: "kitten mewing"
    },
    {
        question_text: "Cats sense of ___ is one of the best in the world.",
        answers: [
            "Smell",
            "Hearing",
            "Sight",
            "Taste"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Hearing",
        image: "https://www.google.com/url?sa=i&source=images&cd=&ved=2ahUKEwjj8_LSsZ7jAhVECc0KHZKiBN8QjRx6BAgBEAU&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.thehappycatsite.com%2Fwhen-do-cats-stop-growing%2F&psig=AOvVaw3JMXMjc4OC3fc3YA0b6Hmx&ust=1562437027702191",
        alt: "kitten mewing"
    },
    {
        question_text: "Kittens are fully weaned at ___ weeks old.",
        answers: [
            "12",
            "2",
            "8",
            "4"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "8",
        image: "https://www.google.com/url?sa=i&source=images&cd=&ved=2ahUKEwjj8_LSsZ7jAhVECc0KHZKiBN8QjRx6BAgBEAU&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.thehappycatsite.com%2Fwhen-do-cats-stop-growing%2F&psig=AOvVaw3JMXMjc4OC3fc3YA0b6Hmx&ust=1562437027702191",
        alt: "kitten mewing"
    },
    {
        question_text: "Male cats are called ___.",
        answers: [
            "Billies",
            "Freds",
            "Jakes",
            "Toms"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Toms",
        image: "https://www.google.com/url?sa=i&source=images&cd=&ved=2ahUKEwjj8_LSsZ7jAhVECc0KHZKiBN8QjRx6BAgBEAU&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.thehappycatsite.com%2Fwhen-do-cats-stop-growing%2F&psig=AOvVaw3JMXMjc4OC3fc3YA0b6Hmx&ust=1562437027702191",
        alt: "kitten mewing"
    },
    {
        question_text: "Female cats are called ___.",
        answers: [
            "Queens",
            "Shebas",
            "Maids",
            "Cleos"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Queens",
        image: "https://www.google.com/url?sa=i&source=images&cd=&ved=2ahUKEwjj8_LSsZ7jAhVECc0KHZKiBN8QjRx6BAgBEAU&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.thehappycatsite.com%2Fwhen-do-cats-stop-growing%2F&psig=AOvVaw3JMXMjc4OC3fc3YA0b6Hmx&ust=1562437027702191",
        alt: "kitten mewing"
    },
    {
        question_text: "A group of cats is called a ___.",
        answers: [
            "Murder",
            "Clowder",
            "Passle",
            "Flock"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Clowder",
        image: "https://www.google.com/url?sa=i&source=images&cd=&ved=2ahUKEwjj8_LSsZ7jAhVECc0KHZKiBN8QjRx6BAgBEAU&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.thehappycatsite.com%2Fwhen-do-cats-stop-growing%2F&psig=AOvVaw3JMXMjc4OC3fc3YA0b6Hmx&ust=1562437027702191",
        alt: "kitten mewing"
    },
    {
        question_text: "There are approximately ___ different breeds of cat in the world.",
        answers: [
            "120",
            "15",
            "70",
            "40"
        ],
        correctAnswer: "70",
        image: "https://www.google.com/url?sa=i&source=images&cd=&ved=2ahUKEwjj8_LSsZ7jAhVECc0KHZKiBN8QjRx6BAgBEAU&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.thehappycatsite.com%2Fwhen-do-cats-stop-growing%2F&psig=AOvVaw3JMXMjc4OC3fc3YA0b6Hmx&ust=1562437027702191",
        alt: "kitten mewing"
    },
    {
        question_text: "On average a cats sleep about ___ hours per day.",
        answers: [
            "5",
            "20",
            "16",
            "10",
        ],
        correctAnswer: "16",
        image: "https://www.google.com/url?sa=i&source=images&cd=&ved=2ahUKEwjj8_LSsZ7jAhVECc0KHZKiBN8QjRx6BAgBEAU&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.thehappycatsite.com%2Fwhen-do-cats-stop-growing%2F&psig=AOvVaw3JMXMjc4OC3fc3YA0b6Hmx&ust=1562437027702191",
        alt: "kitten mewing"
    },
    {
        question_text: "A haw is the third ___ of a cat.",
        answers: [
            "Eyelid",
            "Front toe",
            "Lip",
            "Ear",
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Eyelid",
        image: "https://www.google.com/url?sa=i&source=images&cd=&ved=2ahUKEwjj8_LSsZ7jAhVECc0KHZKiBN8QjRx6BAgBEAU&url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.thehappycatsite.com%2Fwhen-do-cats-stop-growing%2F&psig=AOvVaw3JMXMjc4OC3fc3YA0b6Hmx&ust=1562437027702191",
        alt: "kitten mewing"
    },
];

let currentQuestionIndex = 0;
let numCorrect = 0;
let numIncorrect = 0;


function startQuizButton() {
    //when the start quiz button is clicked
    //will begin questions
    $("#quizKittens").on("submit", function (event) {
        event.preventDefault();
        $("button.pounceStart").toggleClass("hidden");
        $("#questionsContent").toggleClass("hidden");
        $(".currentQuestion").text(1);
        renderNextQuestion();
    });
}

function renderNextQuestion() {
    let currentQuestion = QUIZ[currentQuestionIndex]

    $("#questionHeader").text(currentQuestion.question_text);

    $("#option1 > span").text(currentQuestion.answers[0]);
    $("#option2 > span").text(currentQuestion.answers[1]);
    $("#option3 > span").text(currentQuestion.answers[2]);
    $("#option4 > span").text(currentQuestion.answers[3]);

    $("#option1 > input").val(currentQuestion.answers[0]);
    $("#option2 > input").val(currentQuestion.answers[1]);
    $("#option3 > input").val(currentQuestion.answers[2]);
    $("#option4 > input").val(currentQuestion.answers[3]);
}

function buttonSubmitQuestion() {
    //when answerSubmissionForm is pressed
    //submit answer
    //Should iterate through each question one at a time
    //Should not skip questions

    $("#answerSubmissionForm").on("submit", function (event) {
        event.preventDefault();
        $("#questionsContent").toggleClass("hidden");
        $("#answerFeedbackAlert").toggleClass("hidden");
         submittedQuestionValues()
        
    })
}

function submittedQuestionValues(){
    let submittedAnswer = $("input[name=answer]:checked", "#answerSubmissionForm").val();

        let correctAnswer = QUIZ[currentQuestionIndex].correctAnswer
        if (submittedAnswer === correctAnswer) {
            $("#answerCorrectAlert").toggleClass("hidden");
            numCorrect++;
            $("#numCorrect").text(numCorrect);
        } else {
            $("#answerIncorrectAlert").toggleClass("hidden");
            $("#correctAnswerHere").text(correctAnswer);
            numIncorrect++;
            $("#numIncorrect").text(numIncorrect);
        }
}
function setupNextButtonForm() {
    $("#nextQuestionForm").on("submit", function (event) {
        event.preventDefault();

        $("#answerFeedbackAlert").toggleClass("hidden");

        if (currentQuestionIndex === QUIZ.length - 1) {
            $("#totalEndScore").toggleClass("hidden");
            $("#totalScoreNum").text(numCorrect);
            console.log("go");
        } else {
            $("#questionsContent").toggleClass("hidden");
            updateQuestionNumber();
            resetQuestionState();
            renderNextQuestion();
        }
    });
}

function resetQuestionState() {
    $("#answerCorrectAlert").addClass("hidden");
    $("#answerIncorrectAlert").addClass("hidden");
    resetRadioButtons(); 
}

function resetRadioButtons(){
    $("#option1 > input").prop("checked", false);
    $("#option2 > input").prop("checked", false);
    $("#option3 > input").prop("checked", false);
    $("#option4 > input").prop("checked", false);
}



function updateQuestionNumber() {
    // increment forward one page
    //update question number
    currentQuestionIndex++;
    $(".currentQuestion").text(currentQuestionIndex + 1);
}

function quizRestartSetup() {
    $("#quizRestartForm").on("submit", function (event) {
        event.preventDefault();

        $("#totalEndScore").toggleClass("hidden");

        $("button.pounceStart").toggleClass("hidden");

        numCorrect = 0;
        $("#numCorrect").text(numCorrect);
        numIncorrect = 0;
        $("#numIncorrect").text(numIncorrect);
        currentQuestionIndex = 0;
        $(".currentQuestion").text(currentQuestionIndex);

        resetQuestionState();
    });

}

$(document).ready(function () {
    startQuizButton();
    buttonSubmitQuestion();
    setupNextButtonForm();
    quizRestartSetup();
});


